IAN HAY, ACA

(+65) 9101 8640 | ian.c.hay69@gmail.com

CHIEF OPERATING / FINANCIAL OFFICER

Internationally Experienced Listed Company CFO / COO with over 20 years of experience in directing core finance and operating activities to sustain growth in fast-paced business environments; especially in the private equity, infrastructure and specialised funds' domains. Progressive leadership experiences have created a passion for revenue growth/cost reduction through skilful business transformations, continuous process improvements, and successful financial modelling (investment vehicle and tax structures).

Team leader with excellent communication skills, a keen eye for detail, and a flair for motivating and mentoring high performance teams.

<u>Computer Skills:</u> MS Word/Excel/PowerPoint (advanced); PeopleSoft; iManage; General Ledger packages (MS Dynamics, MYOB)

CORE COMPETENCIES

Streamlining and strengthening financial operations ◆ Management decision-making and strategy
Financial control and reporting ◆ Business transformation management ◆ Finance function
setup, development of financial processes ◆ Financial operations management for
private equity and listed investment vehicles ◆ Compliance management ◆ Tax
structuring ◆ Debt facilities' negotiations ◆ Risk management and systems'
setup ◆ Treasury ◆ Company secretarial functions ◆ Acquisition and
investment vehicle structure support ◆ Financial consultancy
Team mentoring ◆ Leadership ◆ Stakeholder engagement

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

CURRENT ROLE

HARBOUR 2 ORGANISATION Singapore

CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICER (CFO) AND DIRECTOR AUGUST 2015-TO DATE

- Business Founder Established Real estate management Company to source, develop and manage Hospitality and Leisure assets in Europe, Middle East and Asia. Namely Hotels, Marinas, Condominiums, Water Sports.
- ♦ Instrumental in fund raising and developing tax structures, negotiating debt facilities, and negotiating acquisition and disposals of assets.
- ♦ Due to nature of start-up responsible for all commercial and office activities in Singapore. I.e. Accounting function, Company Secretarial and Legal, office management, relationship liaison.

KEPPEL DC REIT (FORMERLY KNOWN AS SECURUS DATA PROPERTY FUND PTE LTD, Singapore *Apr 2011–May 2015*)

(Listed via IPO Dec 2014 – on SGX Asia's 1st Pure-Play Data Centre REIT.)

CHIEF FINANCIAL OFFICER (CFO)

- ♦ Lead Project for IPO of REIT (listed on Singapore Stock Exchange Dec 2014) liaise with advisers, potential investors, regulators, and internal and external stakeholders
- Provide leadership for competent management of financial, compliance, and reporting activities
 of this Singapore-based fund. Also, manage Fund's six international investments and their
 intermediate holding entities
 - o Instrumental in developing **tax structures**, negotiating debt facilities, and managing financial reporting of all six properties
 - Successfully negotiated debt facilities worth over US\$230 million
- ♦ **Skilfully** manage FX and profit rate risks; and formulate tax strategies across multiple jurisdictions such as UK, Guernsey, Singapore, Australia, Holland, Republic of Ireland, and Malaysia

lan Hay Page 2 of 3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

KEPPEL DC REIT CFO (continued)

♦ Spearhead initiatives to setup Fund's internal finance function – implement General Ledger processes, design and deploy financial consolidation software and payroll system, and develop new financial control and reporting framework

 The internal finance function was setup with limited technical assistance and at minimum costs, as is the norm with start-up enterprises

ASTRO JAPAN PROPERTY GROUP, Sydney, NSW, Australia (ASX listed property group which invests in the real estate market of Japan.)

Apr 2008-Feb 2011

CFO AND HEAD OF OPERATIONS – Australia

- Directed efforts for managing Group's commercial as well as operations' functions including financial control and strategy, modelling/scenario analysis, treasury, taxation, human resources, investor relations, premises management, and regulatory matters (ASIC and ASX reporting)
- ♦ Reduced annual operations' costs (during global financial crisis) from A\$4.5 million to A\$3 million by decreasing headcount and overheads, outsourcing non-key functions, and amalgamating job roles
- ♦ Led and **mentored** legal, company secretarial, and risk functions' heads
- ♦ Recognised for ensuring **smooth business transformation** of Australian operations during separation of Astro Japan from Babcock & Brown, through internalisation of management rights (complex sale process over five months and with a value of **A\$45 million** project)
 - Liaised with investment banks for structuring, pricing, and modelling deal; coordinated with legal advisers for documentation; and negotiated commercial terms with Babcock & Brown
 - Post-internalisation, renegotiated Astro Japan's derivatives portfolio secured important waiver from counterparty and successfully monetised hedging instruments (portfolio value at time of negotiation: A\$100 million)
 - Downsized and built additional competencies of team, supervised relocation of operations (away from Babcock & Brown Group), and deployed a new IT system for Astro Japan
- ♦ Designed, developed, and implemented a **detailed financial model** for navigating company through global financial crisis of 2008 assessed property portfolio, debt, and treasury position; negotiated with Banks to ensure liquidity; and monitored strategic sales

ALLCO FINANCE GROUP, Sydney, NSW, Australia

Nov 2007-Mar 2008

(Fully integrated global financial services business, now undergoing liquidation.)

GLOBAL FINANCE DIRECTOR – Infrastructure

- ♦ Led and managed a team of six personnel for providing finance and reporting support to Allco's infrastructure division
- ♦ Provided acquisition and structuring support to origination team acquiring European and North American wind farms, Consolidated Edison's power station in New York State, and alternative energy start-up businesses in Australia

MACQUARIE GROUP LTD., London, UK (Global investment banking and diversified financial services group.)

Jan 1999-Nov 2007

ASSOCIATE DIRECTOR (2001–2007)

- ♦ Solely accountable for finance, treasury, taxation, and company secretarial functions of Infrastructure and Specialised Funds division
 - Established division's finance function, enabling detailed and relevant reporting for Macquarie's infrastructures assets across Europe

lan Hay Page 3 of 3

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

MACQUARIE GROUP LTD., (continued)

Led business development efforts, supporting a growing front office team (grew from 13 people to 87 personnel, including 75 personnel supported by new finance team of 12 people)

- Also, managed finances for expanded investment portfolio grew from one listed investment vehicle to six investment vehicles (three private equity and three listed)
- ♦ Investment Vehicles Managed (Private equity and listed on ASX):
 - Managed financial operations for European arms of Macquarie Communications Infrastructure Group and Macquarie Capital Alliance Group
 - Northern Hemisphere's CFO for Macquarie European Infrastructure plc, £1 billion toll road investor with key investments in M6Toll in Birmingham, UK and ETR407 in Ontario Canada
 - Fund's CFO for Macquarie Airports Group, €600 million closed private equity fund owning stakes in Birmingham, Bristol, Rome, and Sydney Airports
 - Fund's CFO for Macquarie European Infrastructure Fund, €422 million (at first close) limited partnership owning controlling stakes in South East Water (UK-based utility company) and Arlanda A-Train Express (Swedish Railway corporation)
- ♦ Appointed as **internal financial consultant**, accountable for providing CFO and business transformation support for recently acquired assets of Group's Managed Funds division
- Drove process changes to align investments with Group's reporting and control structure. Key projects included:
 - Interim CFO of San Diego Expressway, California (following acquisition and pending appointment of local CFO)
 - o Seconded to Argiva Communications as Group Financial Controller for six months
 - Numerous integration and consultancy projects for European assets acquired by Macquarie-sponsored infrastructure vehicles – established systems, trained teams, and implemented processes and controls. **Key projects** included Cintra (Spanish toll roads), Rome and Brussels airports, Tanquid (German petrochemical storage tanks), and BBC Broadcast (provider of artistic and creative services to BBC)

FINANCE MANAGER (1999–2001)

- ♦ Supervised accounting support team, managing accounting for Infrastructure and Specialised Funds division, and Technology Investment Banking division
- ♦ Managed accounting for Macquarie Infrastructure Group (MIG), which, grew from a new investment vehicle to one of the top twenty market capitalised entities on ASX

PRIOR EXPERIENCE

- ♦ Second-in-Charge to Group Financial Controller, KLZ Ltd., Australia, 1996–1998
- ♦ Auditor, Coopers & Lybrand, Europe and Australia, 1988–1996

EDUCATION

Chartered Accountant (ACA) (1994)

Institute of Chartered Accountants of England and Wales, UK

Member – Institute of Accounting Technicians, UK (1991)

~ References Available on Request ~